freedom man, that's what it's all about
[Music]
you've got to groove on freedom like the
good book says
[Music]
welcome, you are listening to what on
earth is happening, this show will
discuss the topics of human
consciousness
mind control
natural law
the occult
and all issues that affect the freedom
of the people of earth
what on earth is happening will endeavor
to shine light
upon the darkness of our world
and to offer empowering solutions to the
problems we face as humanity approaches
its critical moment of choice
and now
here is your host
mark
passio
[Music]
welcome one and all, you're watching what
on earth is happening, i'm your host, mark
passio, my website whatonearthishappening.com
ladies and gentlemen, government
is
slavery
and here on what on earth is happening
we are ending slavery one mind at a time
welcome everyone, thank you for tuning in
today
today is episode number 251 of what on
earth is happening, it is sunday april
24th, 2022, we have a great show lined up
for you here today, we are going to be
exploring
in a
beginners, in an
introductory sense
the occult philosophy known as thelema
really for the first time officially
here on what on earth is happening i
covered it
in
another podcast with bob from cincinnati
on his show "occult empire" years ago, but
we'll be breaking down the occult
philosophy called thelema
and what it's really about
on this very program, so, if you're going to
want to stay tuned in for that - that's
coming up in a short while
i do want to switch over to my laptop
and go through a couple of housekeeping
announcements before we jump into the
main material for today
last week we were off for easter
i hope everybody had a good easter and
you know, we're back into programming
this week, and
the how to become the true media seminar
is coming at us rapidly, we are filling
up the seats of the seminar
so, let me jump over to the laptop
thank you to Will Keller for the great
artwork, as always
again, the topic for today the occult
philosophy of thelema, it's gonna be
something that
some people are gonna get and hopefully
they will
research more deeply into it, and some
people will never understand
they will insist that this is
something that i shouldn't even be
discussing or talking about, and, you know
insist it's what other people
have told them that it is, instead
of them looking at it for themselves and
deciding what it really is, from
personal first-hand investigation
so, we're on the new format, of course
for a six-month schedule from january
through june
after which
i will be hosting and teaching the how
to become the true media seminar
again, how to become the true media 2022
coming at us this july
seats are filling up, so, if you want to
reserve your spot
enrollment is now open
and
it closes on july 4th of this year
that's one week before the seminar
begins
this is a seminar that will teach you
everything that you need to know
regarding how to do
what i do
if you want to start a video podcast, if
you want to start an audio podcast, if
you want to start a website, if you want
to put videos out and talk about what's
going on in the world, and help to
enlighten other people
and help to make them aware of what's
really taking place
instead of what the lying
prostitute mainstream media tells them
this is the seminar for you, if you feel
like you have gotten the material
that i have been discussing and teaching
to date
but you
yourself
know that you need to teach it to others
and you just don't know how to go about
doing that, and how to begin that process
this is the seminar
this is what will teach you all of those
steps from the very beginning
it's a 23-week intensive seminar
we're going to be talking about a lot of
different technological aspects, from
like i said
everything from
the file system, how to organize
files, to making an outline of your
thoughts
to making presentations
slides like this
graphics
up through audio, video and making your
own website to
keep a central repository of all your
work and distribute it out there to
others
so, the seminar this year is taking place
every monday evening 8 to 11 pm eastern
time, from monday july 11th through
monday december 12, 2022
that's a total of 23 class sessions
there is limited space available
in this technology seminar, we're hosting
it on telegram this year
a couple of questions have come up, you
do need a cell phone
to at least get enrolled in the seminar
i really don't recommend
taking the seminar on a smartphone
but you're going to need a cell phone at
least to get enrolled, because
a cell phone is required to download the
telegram mobile app
after which
you can download the telegram desktop
app, which i recommend taking the course
on
and in order to get that linked to your
mobile account you do need to download
the smartphone app, so, there were a
couple questions regarding that you do
need a smartphone in order to get
telegram installed on your computer, on
your desktop or laptop computer, because
it makes you take a
picture of the qr code, and that is how
it links the desktop app to the mobile
app
so, i just wanted to put that out there
for anyone that did have a question
regarding what is needed, all that is
needed is a
desktop or laptop computer that is
capable of running the telegram desktop
app, but you do need a cell phone to get
registered
and to get the
telegram desktop app linked to the
mobile app, that just should be
clarified and hopefully that takes care
of that
for more information on how to become
the true media and to click through to
the enrollment page
visit howtobecomethetruemedia.com
do not wait
class seats are filling up
still running the t-shirt special
clearance
all t-shirts on what on earth is
happening 40 to 50 percent off until
stock is gone
i think we have about 10 t-shirts left
total
so
get them now, you know, they're
obviously in limited
sizes and colors, now, that were
rapidly running out, i'll be putting a
new t-shirt order in the next
week or two, and we should have those
shirts in, probably, about a month
so, we'll be back totally in stock
with all
designs and colors, but if you want to
take advantage of the clearance special
40 to 50 percent off all regular
t-shirts short sleeve t-shirts are over
fifty percent off
about fifty one fifty two percent
and all long sleeve t-shirts that we
have left in stock are about forty 41
off
so take advantage of this clearance
special
while there are still a few shirts left
you can visit gifts dot what on earth is
happening dot com to take advantage of
that
t-shirt clearance
check out the one great work network
onegreatworknetwork.com
60 phenomenal content creators all
teaching
natural law objective morality teaching
people what's really going on in our
world
teaching the occult and the occult
sciences absolutely
definitely check out and support all the
great content creators on the network
and do support them they all have
donation pages as well so please support
them individually that's what makes this
network keep going it is entirely
supported by viewer donations
we don't charge for anything on the
network
no one is charged or has to pay any fees
it's completely open
100 percent free
we're trying to keep it that way so do
support everyone who's on the network
and if you're inclined to make a
donation to the network there is a
donate page for that as well on the main
website at onegreatworknetwork.com
the wall on earth is happening ipfs
project is still going
if you're interested in taking part in
it visit whatonearthishappening.com slash
ipfs
the main requirement to run an ipfs
server for distributing what on earth is
happening material
if it you're going to be officially
involved in doing that through through
me
is that you need a
home internet connection of 200 megabits
per second or greater in the upstream or
upload direction
if you don't have that - that will not
qualify you to take part in this project
but if you do you can fill in the form
and get the preliminary requirements and
technical specifications of what you're
going to need at
whatonearthishappening.com slash
ipfs
if there is time today i will be taking
calls on discord, i don't know if we will
have time, but
possibly, depends on how quickly i go
through the material
if not - we'll definitely do an
all-call-in show on this topic at some
point
i may extend the topic into a second
week, we'll see how things go
i may want to do more reading into
some seminal works of thelema
if i don't have time to do that today
hopefully there will be time
but if we have some extra time i'll
be taking calls today, you can go to whatonearthishappening.com slash
discord
that will enter you into our
calling room on the server
and
you could also visit the show page at
whatonearthishappening.com slash
show and there is a discord widget on
the show page, as well
just
briefly step out of my slides before
continuing
i want to just check something really
quick
yes i wasn't in the calling room on the
server, i just fixed that
alright, let's go back over to the
slides
there we go
alright
the ark 2.0 drive is still available
this offer is ongoing, people take me up
on this just about every single day
i am very impressed with how many people
have
requested the ark offer
and taken advantage of it
and
i am just can almost barely keep up with
them sometimes, sometimes i have 3 or
4, or 5 in the house at the same
time
the ark drive is a collection of all of
my research data, not my material, but
an eclectic array of researchers over
the years that i've been downloading
since i've been online, since back in the
mid 90s
and
this two terabyte hard drive contains 26000 audio files
9500 books and 3400 videos from my own
personal archive of research and data
gathered over the years
and put on the, copied onto the two
terabyte drive that you provide
if you want to take advantage of this
unique offer that gets around internet
censorship, doesn't require searching the
web, doesn't require downloading - it's all
there on a drive that you can connect to
any
computer, any computing device
mac, windows
linux
visit whatonearthishappening.com
slash ark
and download, fill in the form and
download the pdf document with the
shipping instructions
on how to take advantage of the ark
drive offer, people are doing this every
single day i thank everybody who has
taken part in the ark offer
we've gotten a lot of information out
there to people this way, so
check it out whatonearthishappening.com slash ark
if you want hard copies of my work in
flash drive format, in hd or dvd format
and other items such as t-shirts
stickers
the complete
one great work collection - it's a flash
drive with all of my data that i've all
of my material personally that i have
ever done since i've started what on
earth is happening, that's the one great
work collection drive
my natural law documentary is up there
we have
coasters, we have buttons
you know ancillary items like that, key
chains
visit
gifts.whatonearthishappening.com, that is
the site
of what on earth is happening donation
gifts
in return for your voluntary donation
i will send you the gifts of your choosing
gifts.whatonearthishappening.com, check it out
if you prefer to make a straight
donation to the what on earth is
happening  and the one great work
network, of course, you could do that in
many ways
through our
donation page at whatonearthishappening.com slash donate
many, many ways to make a donation there
cash app g pay wise bitcoin bitcoin cash
litecoin ethereum dash and our amazon
wish list
for technology which is currently empty
we have the technology we need right now
there's nothing
that wall on earth is happening
currently is wanting for technologically
so that's a good good thing and thank
you to everyone who has made generous
donations over the years
also check and money order is uh they're
available as it is for enrollment in the
how to become the true media seminar and
uh many people have taken advantage of
that and have enrolled that way already
this year
so, that's all the housekeeping
announcements for now, let's jump into
our main material which is the occult
philosophy of thelema
and
the first thing i'm going to talk about
is the pronunciation of thelema
a lot of people out there say "thelima"
i hear this all the time, because they're
pronouncing the second "e"
"thelema" is spelled t-h-e-l-e-m-a
and in greek the second "e" is a long "ei"
sound
if you write the word thelema in greek
it is theta, epsilon, lambda, eta
okay
mu
alpha
it is not another epsilon, or it is not
an aiota or an iota
which would be pronounced "thelema" or "thelima"
it is a long "ei" sound, the eta sound in
thelema, when you see it written in greek
as i'll have it up there in a moment
that eta
that's how you pronounce the
character in ancient greek eta
and then it is written in english as an
"h"
and in ancient greek eta is
pronounced "ei", long "ei", so, without a doubt
unequivocally
definitively
it is correct, it is true
that the word thelema is pronounced just
as i pronounced it - "thelema"
okay
i hear people who claim to be thelemites
pronouncing it "thelima", and that's just the
bastardization of the pronunciation
here we're seeing the main
symbol of the philosophy, some people
would refer to it as a religion, i don't
i consider it an occult philosophy, a
philosophy that is born
out of many other schools of
philosophical occult thought, and other
occultic traditions
and sort of is an aggregate of many of
them
this is the symbol known as the
unicursal hexagram
which simply means that it is a hexagram
or
two interlaced
triangles of of a sort
representing the chalice and the blade
the sacred feminine wed together with
the sacred masculine
the chalice being the sacred feminine
womb or cup
and then the sacred masculine being the
blade or phallic symbol, we've talked
about this symbolism pretty much
endlessly on what on earth is happening
in the early parts of the series when
i break down symbolism
and, by the way, this show is... is cumulative material, so, i want to say
at the beginning of just about every
show
you have to go back and you have to
listen to the shows in order, this is
episode number 251, without the benefit
of understanding the other 250 episodes
this show is not going to make as much
sense to you, each show of what on earth
is happening does not stand alone
there is prerequisite material to
understand in the earlier episodes
so, if you are a new viewer or listener
you should go back to the early earliest
episode - show number 1, and you should
listen in order
from 1 to 2, to 3, to 4, to 5
etcetera
at your own pace
that is the only way you're going to
gain maximum benefit and maximum clarity
and maximum understanding of what i talk
about here on this program
so
going back to the symbolism of thelema
the unicursal hexagram
is one of its main symbols because it
represents
the balancing of the sacred masculine
and sacred feminine energies in sacred
union
the alchemical wedding, as it has been
known, as it has been called in different
occult traditions
and
it is
a little bit different from the
traditional usage of the combination of
the chalice and blade in what is known
as the seal of solomon or the six-pointed star
and
aleister crowley, the founder of the
tradition of thelema, who we will talk
about a little bit, i'm not going to get
very, very deeply into crowley in his
life
crowley, crawley, however anyone wants to
pronounce that
i generally pronounce it crowley, but
we'll get into crowley in his life
and we won't get that much into it
i'm going to talk about how you can't
equivalate
crowley and thelema, crowley may be the
founder and popularizer of the thelemic
tradition in the world of the occult
but he does not represent the beyond
end-all of what thelema is, nor should
anyone look to his life as an example
and attempt to live according to how
crowley lived, that would be a very bad
way of going about representing
exploring the thelemic tradition etcetera
so, we'll get into the
details of that in a moment, because
that's one of the first things people
are going to ask, but i want to speak a
little bit to the symbolism, since this
is how i'm entering
the topic
with this slide
crowley wanted to
unify the chalice and the blade in a way
that it hadn't been before
with the seal of solomon, in which they
are each represented separately
they either overlap or interlock in that
symbol
he wanted to write it
down on paper without picking up the
pencil or pen that he's writing with, so
that's what is meant by unicursal, it's
drawn with one movement
okay, you could draw this symbol with one
movement, it joins itself, it's not broken
okay, so, i'll put the cursor here, so you
could see it, if you started in this
corner
you go up here to the top, and then down
to this corner, and then over
and then you draw then the chalice
and then you're back where you began
so, that's what is meant by unicursal, it
is in one
movement of
the pen or pencil on the paper
and then in the middle of it, at the
heart, and this is a point of contention
as well, in the symbolism
there is a five petaled flower
some people
present this symbol inverted with the
top point of the five-pointed petaled
flower, five-petaled flower
pointed down
i don't see that as the correct
orientation, but people argue this over
and over again, and you will see it in
the thelemic tradition in both
orientations, pointed up and down
to me, and this should be no surprise to
anyone that knows my work
i would say the correct orientation is
with the
the fifth point of the pedal pointing
upward
because this puts
the
orientation of the petal of the flower
in its correct orientation, because that
fifth petal represents spirit
in the
tradition of elements alchemically, you
have earth, air, water and fire as being
the elements that make up the material
plane
and then, of course, spirit
is the fifth element
or you could see that as love or just
consciousness
and that always should be above
the others, not in the sense that it is
quote more important
but it is the
the unifying aspect of it, it is
something that should not be in a
downward position where the
physical
elements take precedence over the
spiritual
so, we talked about that a lot, when we
talked about the five-pointed pentagram
and how it should be always in an
upright orientation, satanists will use
it in the inverted orientation
and that was going to bring us
that kind of completes what i wanted to
say about the unicursal hexagram and why
it is the
sort of foundational
and known symbol of the thelemic
tradition
but in talking about the correct
orientation of that five-petaled flower
in the heart of the unicursal
hexagram
that sort of brings us to the next
topic and point of contention, when it
comes to thelema
what almost everybody is going to say is
why even discuss thelema ? why
delve into this topic, mark ?
isn't thelema satanism ? isn't that
the stuff that aleister crowley was into
and wasn't crowley himself a satanist
almost everybody who is unfamiliar with
the tradition of thelema and has not
studied it in depth
is going to come up with this very
wording this question, these questions
that... you know
it's one of the first things that people
are going to ask
and unequivocally without a shadow of a
doubt
thelema is not satanism
they are entirely different things, now
that does not mean that
it cannot be perverted and used in a
satanic way - is kabbalah satanism ? no it
is not
can kabbalah be used in a negative
aspect
in a satanic aspect - yes, it can
in the dark aspect of kabbalah, that
is
known as
klippoth, we've talked about that a little
bit on previous episodes of what on
earth is happening, the klippothic kabbalah
klippothic kabbalah
is the inversion of true kabbalistic
tradition
in occultism
because, if you know this knowledge
and you hold it, and you have a deep
understanding of it, and you wanted to
manipulate someone that has no
understanding of it
that is possible to do
if you're of that low consciousness
so
can kabbalah be twisted and turned around
and turned into a satanic tradition ?
yes
rosicrucianism is not satanism
however - is there a dark side to that ? yes
there can be
look at the people who put up
the georgia guidestones and claim that
the person's name was r.c. christian
or in other words, rose-cross christian
which is what
a rosicrucian is - a christian of the rose-cross, rosic-crucian, rose-cross
after the
allegorical founder of the rose-cross
tradition, the rosicrucian tradition
christian rosencreutz, christian r.c.
again, that's who the Georgia Guidestones
which are clearly
born of a satanic mindset
to try to cull the population down to
manageable numbers for the satanic
elitists
so, can rosicrucianism be turned around
and made into a dark tradition ? yes, it
can
that does not mean there is not a pure
unadulterated form of it, look at
freemasonry
we taught freemasonry for a few months
here on what on earth is happening, in
many episodes
some
high-level freemasons
got in touch with me after those
broadcasts, and even subsequently later
years later
and told me - you've taught me more
about freemasonry than
all my years in the lodge, and i've had
people personally who belong to lodge
systems of freemasonry tell me that
because
many of their traditions have turned
to the dark side, they're not teaching
the esoteric traditions of freemasonry
they're a disgrace
most of the lodges
let me tell you what i want, i'm going
off on an aside about this, because i'm
trying to emphasize the point, first of
all, that every occult tradition can have
a dark side, because it's about knowledge
and how it is used
that does not make
thelema satanism just because crowley, as
a man
failed
to stay upon the path of thelema
with his
earthly self
and his earthly will
crowley is no more thelema, ladies and
gentlemen
than any worshipful master
at a masonic lodge anywhere in the world
is freemasonry
crowley is no more thelema
then
mark passio is natural law
what hubris i would have to have the
claim that i am natural law, of course
i'm not
i can understand how it works and relate
that to others
but that doesn't make me that
thing
so, crowley is not the tradition of thelema, and anybody that insists that he is
is sorely mistaken and or lying
but this is the problem that happens, and
i want to, i do want to go off on an
aside regarding freemasonry as a matter
of fact, crowley integrated a lot of
different traditions into thelema
rosicrucianism, kabbalah, of course, tarot
absolutely, i will show some of
a couple of the tarot cards from his own
personal deck, the thoth deck
in this broadcast
and
again, he fell from the path of thelema
and some would call that a satanic path
he went down the left-hand path
but that doesn't make the tradition
and the philosophy of thelema satanic
again, let's say, i fall from the path of
natural law
and that's absolutely possible, anything
can happen in an individual's life
that does not make
everything i said about natural law
invalid
crowley, falling from the path of thelema, does not make what he said about
what is true regarding the philosophy of
thelema and the path of thelema
invalid
it just makes him an asshole, and it
makes him
having done made poor choices in life
and having done bad things
that does not invalidate the philosophy
this is a very mature mindset, that has
to be first of all developed
upon the part of the potential student
of an occult tradition like thelema
that's why i tell people
this is last in the line
you know
study simpler occult traditions, i like
to tell people - study the tarot, honestly
if you're going to delve into an occult
tradition first, when you know nothing
about it, the symbolism of the tarot is
very neutral
and when you decode it - it teaches such
wonderful things that
it's a great place to start, as far as
i'm concerned, it can
get
somewhat
involved and
complicated too, as well, but that just
challenges your mind
kabbalah is the same way, there's so many
different symbolic, you know
overtones to it, tons of symbolism
wording
cross-correlations, you need
correlative thinking to understand it
and it challenges the mind, and it brings
the brain hemispheres into unison with
each other
gets them firing on all cylinders
that's why i love the kabbalistic
tradition, that's why
when i decided what occult traditions am
i going to really teach in earnest here
on what on earth is happening - tarot and
kabbalah were two of the first that
needed to be studied in conjunction with
each other
that's very true of thelema, you're not
going to understand the thelemic
tradition without
a firm foundation in other forms of
occultism such as tarot, kabbalah
freemasonry and rosicrucianism
especially
so, let's clear up this question once and
for all, and get that out of the way
you could say - crowley fell from the
thelemic path and lived a satanic
lifestyle for
a good amount of time
but do not equate crowley with thelema
once again, we have to
take the very adult
perspective
and
attempt to separate the human being
from the information that they espouse
or that they are talking about, or that
they are trying to communicate
so, people may not like mark passio, and
that's fine
i'm not required to be liked, i don't
require anyone to like me
but
is what i'm saying about natural law
true ? yes, it is
so
again
crowley is no more
the equivalent to thelema than mark
passio is the equivalent to natural law
if you don't like hearing about natural
law from mark passio you'll go learn about
it from someone else
so
this is the first thing that has to be
understood is
you have to take the person
separately from the tradition
look at freemasonry
can you
simply
attribute
all of the freemasonic tradition and
all of the philosophy contained therein
to the lodge system ?
the lodge system is not freemasonry
this is why i've told people in studying
freemasonry and in exploring it, and
teaching it
you don't need the lodge system
the lodge system is largely junk today
however, i want to make an aside on this
very point
and especially talking about freemasonry
which is definitely a
a simpatico influence with thelema
i would personally like to be able to
teach inside the freemasonic lodge
system, so, i'm going to put this
idea
offer, however you want to look at it out
there
if a worshipful master of their lodge
anywhere
in the world
wishes to confer upon me the honorary
33rd degree of freemasonry
i would
graciously accept that
conference of the 33rd degree
because and, quite frankly, i feel that it
should be done
and i'm not, i'm not
i'm not directly even like asking or
begging for that, i'm saying - i think it
should be done for a reason, for a
specific reason
the lodge system of freemasonry is in
absolute
junk
disarray
anybody, who
even speaks with anybody within the
systems of freemasonry at work today in
the world, not only knows this, they know
it's way worse than what i'm saying
and you know, you know this
if you don't know it
you're just dumb, son
okay
you should know it if you're
involved in any capacity
so
my kind of idea and or offer for the
lodge system is
if
a worshipful master of a current lodge, a
current worshipful master were to make
me
were to confer upon me the 33rd honorary
degree
for what i have taught regarding
freemasonry during my
career in broadcasting on what on earth
is happening and the other lectures that
i've given in presentations i've done
for the clarification
that i have given to the freemasonic
tradition
and, also, even
helping people to separate it from the
lodge system
once again
crowley is no
more thelema
than the lodge system is freemasonry
they cannot be
considered equivalents of each other
they are not equal to each other, okay
that's the sign there
on the
slide there for not equal to
crowley is not equal to thelema
the lodge system is not equal to
freemasonry, mark passio is not equal to
natural law
you have to separate human beings from
philosophical understanding and ideas
they're not equivalent
and that's discernment, that comes with
discernment
once again, this show's gonna fly over
most people's heads, i'm gonna lose most
people
and that's okay, it's not meant for
everybody, it's not meant for most people
it's meant for the people they're going
to exercise the discernment to really
hear what i'm saying and get it
but going back to this idea of
if i were to be conferred the honorary
33rd degree of freemasonry without
even entering the lodge system like was
done for manly p. hall
like was done for
many other people who the 33rd honorary
degree was conferred to
what it would make possible
is i, as an individual
would then be able to walk into any
lodge system anywhere in the world
any lodge system in the world
i would be able to walk into
make an agreement or arrangement with
people who want to improve their lodge
system
by teaching natural law
and i could go into those environments
and potentially teach
an entire class on natural law
for one of the lodge meetings
and i'd be willing to do that, i would
be willing to offer of my time
in that capacity to make
extra special one-of-a-kind slide
presentation specifically
about the esoteric tradition of
freemasonry, its symbolism
its allegories
and burst that onto the minds of the
people in the lodge system, that perhaps
are not getting it within the teachings
of the lodge, and i know they're not, and
the people out there listening to me, who
are involved in that in those lodge
systems
absolutely no, they're not getting it to
the extent that they need
because i've known a lot of freemasons
over the years, and they've all told me
the exact same thing, and none of it's
getting any better
it's been actually declining and getting
rapidly worse
as things continue to go on, as more and
more influence of political systems and
financial systems come into place, and
into that whole
networking arena of the lodge system
so, my offer - it's an offer of my time
and knowledge
and the way that i do things
and my aesthetic
that i can bring to the table
in a presentation format
if someone in, who is a worshipable
master of their lodge, wants to confer
the honorary 33rd degree upon me
i will teach in
the
lodge system
wherever someone wants to have me
to help
more deeply
the
members of that lodge understand the
allegorical and symbolic aspects of
esoteric masonry
esoteric freemasonry
so, i just want to put that out there
but
going back to this concept is
people have to stop
taking the mindset of
i've heard really bad things about this
person, that person, the other person, so
i'm not going to look into the
philosophy at all
let me tell you exactly what that is, and
exactly what you're playing into the
hands of
you're playing into the hands of the
dark occultists by doing that
the satanists and the dark occultists
want exactly that
let me say that again, so, you fully
understand this
the satanists and the dark occultists
who are really running the world, want
that exact position, they want that
exact mindset to take place in people's
minds, because they don't want you
understanding thelema, they don't want
you understanding tarot, they don't want
you understanding rosicrucianism, they
don't want you understanding freemasonry
they don't want you understanding
kabbalah
they certainly don't want you
understanding thelema, because thelema
could be
the concrescence and
aggregate combined expression of all the
occult traditions that have come before
it
i consider it one of the most advanced
occult philosophies personally
i consider that, when i really, really
deeply understood thelema
and what it was really trying to teach
philosophically
my consciousness expanded so greatly at
that point, and i got so many things, that
i didn't get with clarity and with
precision previously, until i really
understood thelema
so, it's been a profound difference maker
for me, in my
life, and, i think, it can be another
persons' lives if they learn how to
separate crowley from the true thelemic
philosophy
if you could bring that discernment to
the table as an adult thinker
and do that
without just single-mindedly focusing on
crowley's deeds in life
which, once again
no one is telling you to emulate
that is the last thing i would ever do
you do not want to live like this guy
live, you do not want to do some of
the things this guy did
he was a gray
occultist at best
certainly, not a a light occultist
was definitely an elitist
definitely worked for intelligence
agencies, while he was alive
i believe long term he did want
true freedom to express
however
his behaviors were not in alignment with
that
and
he did
many unsavory things
that
i would never tell you to emulate or use
his life example as a guide
certainly, don't use the man as a life
example
it's
the idea of
do as he said, not as he did
because his writings are profound, and
deeply spiritually awakening if one
understands them
he wrote in a lot of code, he wrote in a
lot of cipher, he wrote in a lot of
numerology, and a lot of allegory, he
wanted to encode it, because he wanted
people to work for the understanding
so, everything was a symbol, everything
was, you know, an array of numbers and
meaning, you know, a correlation
correlative meaning
he didn't want to explain things
straight out to de-occult them, see, that's
what we're doing here on what on earth
is happening
this is a de-occulting broadcast
crowley still wanted the information
occulted and kept for
the
initiates, who he felt deserved it
he was still of that hermetic mindset
right
again, hermeticism, we could look at that
tradition, you can look at that
philosophy, which is wonderful
but is there a dark side to the hermetic
tradition ? yes, there is
if you don't understand that - you don't
understand the occult, the occult is a
dual-edged sword of knowledge, it can cut
both ways
and even something like hermeticism
which people
somehow insist was the one that remained
pure throughout the ages
can be turned into a dark tradition, and
an elitist tradition
they didn't get the job done
right ?
did the rosicrucians get the job done ?
is humanity free
as a result of the rosicrucians putting
their knowledge out into the world ?
is humanity free as a result of what
crowley did with thelema ? is humanity
free what the lodge system has done with
freemasonry ?
is humanity free
as a result of what the hermeticists did
with the hermetic tradition and
philosophy ? no
all of them fell short, all of them
failed
that doesn't mean we shouldn't study the
traditions, that doesn't mean we
shouldn't separate the people from the
traditions and the philosophy that they
espoused
and it means that clearly
higher level understanding and knowledge
that needs to be built on those
foundations is required, and that's part
of what i'm attempting to do with what
on earth is happening, and have been
since day one
and, also, trying to teach people the way
that people have gone about teaching the
occult has failed, it has not resulted in
human freedom, we are deeper in bondage
than we were before
and then people want to still insist - we
gotta keep this information from people
that don't deserve it - wrong
it needs to be made common sense
knowledge in an egalitarian fashion
meaning it's out there for anyone who
wants it, and nobody holds it back from
anybody else and considers themselves
the gatekeepers or the holders of
that knowledge
until they deem other people
fit for it
crowley was an elitist like that, and i'm
sure he took that from the hermetic
tradition
and it's a mistake
it was a mistake thousands of years ago
it was a mistake when crowley did it in
the early 1900s
and it's a mistake now to anybody still
doing that
ridiculous
mindset of saying that this knowledge
should be held for an elite few
absolutely incorrect
it should be distributed widely and
freely, and made available for all, so
that it can
become common sense, and that's the only
way humanity is going to become free is
when this knowledge becomes common sense
once again
or, perhaps, for the first time in human
history
probably, more accurate to say
so, then if crowley isn't thelema then
what is thelema ?
thelema spelled in the greek
theta, epsilon, lambda
and this is incorrect here, i have to
correct this, i
said it myself, that it was...
there it is, that is how it is spelled
i apologize for that, let me see if i
have that incorrect
anywhere else, because i'm gonna have to
fix it
i want to just quickly fix that where i
made the error in there putting an
epsilon myself, so, i'm i was thinking
about it, and that's what made me do it
i just want to make sure i don't have
that like that anywhere else
let me step out of the slides real quick
to just go
correct that, so
yeah, let's... that now, that i'm bringing
it up in greek, i'm just going to step
through the slides and just make sure, i
don't have that error anywhere else, i
don't believe that i do, it looks like
everywhere else that it was written
it is correct
so, let me make sure, yeah... yep yep
everywhere else in the presentation it's
correct
so, just on those two slides i had it
spelled
with an epsilon, so, let's
jump back
i apologize for that
alright
there is the correct spelling, so
this is written in the ancient greek
characters
that's a capital theta at the
beginning
then epsilon, then lambda, then eta
then mu, then alpha, so, these characters
in greek, the theta represents the t-h
sound
"th", okay
then you have the epsilon which is the
short "e" sound
"e", then lambda, which is "l" in greek, then
eta, that's this character, right here
that i'm pointing that i'm underlining
with my cursor
sorry, right there, next to... the this is
the lambda, and then this is the eta
right here
it looks like  an elongated "n"
okay
or
an "h" kind of, without the top
piece of the "h"
it would be transliterated into english
as an h
and then, next to that, there's mu
which is an "m"
and then alpha, which is "a", so, read
together it's thelema
t-h-e-l-long ei-m-a
okay, thelema
thelema is an occult philosophy
founded by aleister crowley in the early
nineteen hundreds, one of the main tenets
of thelema
i have another error here
i need the word "is" in there
one of the main tenets of thelema is
the development of one's true will, we're
going to be talking about the concept
throughout the day, throughout this
presentation of the true will - what is
the true will - because will is what
thelema means, "thelema", actually, is the
greek word for "will"
and i probably should write that in here
let's...
let me jump back and
i'll write that right into this
let me see a little bit of what we'll be
teaching, and how to become the true
media, which is
modifying
slides in a slideshow
it's what i do every week and
occasionally i make mistakes
so, there it's fixed
okay
so, i think that reads a little bit
better thelema, the greek word for will
is an occult philosophy
let's even put that in...
inside...
there we go...
i think that reads even better
thelema, and then i'm writing in greek
greek for will - is an occult philosophy
founded by aleister crowley in the early
1900s, one of the main tenets
is the development of one's true will
the life path of a being
who has raised their consciousness into
alignment with universal spiritual law
that is the true will
regardless of what anybody else is going
to attempt to tell you about what
something like
"do what thou wilt shall be the whole of
the law" means, which we will talk about
that information
we will talk about that phrase
okay
and we're going to talk about what is
the true will, what does that phrase mean
what does true will mean in thelemic
philosophy
it means that you're on the spiritual
path, that you are truly meant to be on
that is your purpose in life
and people always leave off the second
part of
do what thou wilt shall be the whole of
the law
they never put the second half of that
phrase which is "love is the law, love
under will" - we're going to be breaking
all of those aspects of that
main tenet of thelema down
we are going to be
talking about what is "do what thou
wilt" mean
what is
"shall be the whole of the law", what does
"love is the law" mean, what is that
phrase mean
what is "love under will" mean
see, without understanding what the
individual components of some of this
philosophy are, what they are all about
you're not going to understand the
totality of the philosophy, you have to
put it all together
but this is the over... in an overarching
sense this is what thelema actually is
it is a occult philosophy
and it is ultimately about the alignment
of one's
life path
to
the will of creation
which is
natural law
as just about every other occult
philosophy, that's what thelema is
ultimately about
so, let's continue
again, that's what i'm explaining here in
this next
part of this slide
like most other occult traditions the
grand purpose of the thelemic philosophy
is to guide its adherence to a deep
understanding of natural law
and align their behaviors to the will of
creation
which would have a great impact in
maximizing human freedom if people were
to do that
if they were to learn
any one of these occult traditions
as we talked about
what is kabbalah's true purpose ?
kabbalah's purpose is about
helping
humanity to align their behavior with
the will of creation, with the will of
the divine
it's about the understanding of the
interrelationship between man and
creation
it's about understanding all the inward
qualities of the self, and how they work
in conjunction with
karma with universal law, to bring about
the external experiences that we then
must live with in life
freemasonry is the same thing, through
its symbols and its allegories it
teaches us how to
align our behavior with universal law
with the laws of the creator of the
universe or as it refers to it as the
grand architect of the universe
thelema is no different in that regard
the tarot, that's all it teaches in its
pictorial symbols, the forces of the
universe, the forces that are indwelling
in the individual, and how they totally
interrelate to each other
as a system of correspondences through
pictorial images
rosicrucianism
teaches the law of one, it teaches
universal love
it teaches heart based intelligence
that's what the rose on the cross is
all about
the heart - that's what the five-petaled
flower is ultimately about at the heart
of the unicursal hexagram of thelema
heart-based intelligence
you know, the heart combined within
the power of the mind and the action of
the body
so, you have body-mind-spirit
the trinity
united
so, let's continue and talk about what
the true will actually is
because when people hear the phrase "do
what thou wilt"
they immediately believe that that means
do whatever you want, and as we're going
to talk about in the next slide
that's the exact opposite of what the
phrase "do what thou wilt" in the thelemic
tradition means
and, once again, you...
you have to acquire this understanding
by reading all of the material in the
tradition
you don't
just immediately pick up the first thing
read it, understand it immediately, and it
tells you everything you need to know
if you're expecting that
don't even bother with thelema, don't
even bother looking into it, you're going
to be sorely disappointed, that's not
what it's for
it's for
delving into something so deeply and not
initially being able to grasp it, that
you turn your mind over to it until you
gain a deep foundational understanding
of it
it's when you read encoded material
it's forcing you to think
at
a higher level, it's forcing you to think
at that correlative level
and that's deliberate, crowley was doing
that deliberately
and then he claims he did some automatic
channel writing, of course
so, who knows, the consciousnesses that
were giving him some of that information
if you believe that, may have been doing
that deliberately, they're encoding it
deliberately
i have some homemade watermelon juice
today, if you've never
folks, just as a complete aside obviously
nutritionally, it's one of the most
hydrating things you could drink, if
you've never juiced watermelon you have
to do it, you just must
and, i mean, get a fresh watermelon
juice the whole thing through a
centrifugal juicer, with the rind, with
the skin and rind, this is technically a
green juice, believe it or not, the bulk
of what's in there is the the green rind
and it's you could consider this a green
juice even though it's like red and
reddish in color
but, the the balance between the rind and
the flesh
makes the glycemic index go down and
it's ultra-ultra hydrating
see
the thelema tradition would include
proper nutrition, as well, would include
taking care of the physical vessel, the
alchemical
aspects and treatments that you could do
to keep the body
optimal
let's go back to
what the true will really is
the true will is the opposite of your
base desires of what you want
what i want to do
what... the comforts that i want
the pleasures that i want, that's has
nothing to do with the true will
the true will
is deferring those things
and or
keeping them at bay at least to the
extent that you can really focus on the
higher will
the true will
true will or thelema
is defined in the thelemic philosophy as
a path of personal action
that operates in harmony with universal
spiritual law, i want to read that
sentence one more time, because
i really want people to understand this
and emphasize what is being said
it's a
the true will is a path of personal
action
it's not your thoughts, it's not your
emotions, it's not your desires, it's not
your wants, it's not what you think
should happen
it's not
coming into total emotional
well-being
it's not bliss
it's none of those things
it is action
that's the key word in there
true will is a path of personal action
it's what you
do
once again, wisdom
is
the top of the trivium, right, you have
knowledge, understanding, wisdom
on the
very top of the kabbalistic tree of life
before you get to the crown
right
kether
when you're so-called crossing the abyss
going into that higher
triangle, at the very top of the tree of
life
if you look at the sefirothic tree
of life in kabbalah
before you get to that top triangle
what is the
sphere
that is there, it is not one of the
seferoth, but it is considered where the
tree grows from, it is daath
d-a-a-t-h
what is that ? knowledge
that's the first step of the trivium
then you go up to
binah
bina is understanding, that's the second
step of the trivium
then you go over to hokma
which is the one right before the crown
that sits at the right hand side of the
crown
kether, hokhmah means wisdom
daath
is not even physical, it's the
hidden realm of knowledge
that is the occult itself, that's the
pure information and potentiality, and
that's where the physical bursts forth
from, that's the root of the tree
and then, the two top parts of the
two pillars on the tree of life
binah and hokhmah
understanding and wisdom, understanding
is an internal process, that's the second
phase of the trivium, once you have the
knowledge you have to make strides to
understand it, weed out all
contradiction, weed out logical
inconsistencies and contradictions, come
to an understanding of what all that
aggregated knowledge means
then what are you going to do with it
just having it and understanding it
doesn't make you good
just having it and understanding it - is
going to accomplish nothing, unless you
do the right things with it
well, when you act rightly upon that
knowledge and understanding - that's
wisdom
so, wisdom is right action
see
so, true will can be considered wisdom
it's a path of personal right action
because it's action that operates in
harmony with universal spiritual law, or
in other words, natural law, when you've
aligned your life path
your actions of your life - with natural
law, and that doesn't just mean
in the negative, in the apathetic not
doing harm, it means teaching natural law
it means you're communicating what is
right to other people, you're
communicating objective morality, you're
living in harmony with natural law
because you become a servant of natural
law
ultimately that's what
creation's will is for its children
whether anybody really wants to accept
the truth of the matter or not, that is
what we are here to learn to do
we are all here to learn
to
listen to the voice of
wisdom
we are here to then become the voice of
wisdom because the creator of the
universe doesn't have a physical voice
in the 3d world
we are to be that voice, we are to put
the law of creation into effect through
our voice
help to express
its understanding through our voice, is a
better way of saying it, so, the people
can then get it and then live their
lives in alignment with it, align their
behavior to it
and this is what thelema helps us to
understand, because it's practices, which
are often meditative practices, yogic
practices, practices of, really again
looking at symbol and allegory
and coming into a level of correlative
thinking, so, that we understand natural
law at a deep fundamental level
and then we're aligning our behavior
with it
so
a path of personal action that operates
in harmony with natural law
distinct and separate from the base will
lower case "w", you notice, everywhere i'm
going to write the word true will - it's
an uppercase "w"
when you see me write will lowercase "w" - that's
i want
that's the ego
that's the personality
okay
that's the role that one is playing in
the world
higher case "w", capital "w", uppercase "w"
is the true will of thelema
lowercase "w" is what do i want for me
my desires
my comfort
what i want to do
as opposed to what i know i need to be
doing, should be doing, must do
totally different
distinct and separate from lower base
desires
true will manifest from the interplay
between the higher self and the whole
universe
once again
that's what
the kabbalistic tradition and the tarot
tradition show us when we study them in
conjunction with each other, when we lay
the tarot cards out on the two trees, the
two kabbalistic trees - the microcosmic
tree and the macrocosmic tree, one shows
us the path to the higher self
from base desires and being stuck in
ignorance to self-mastery, the other tree
shows us the forces of the universe
from judgment, when we remain in base
desires and ignorance, to
natural law, which is justice
when we have applied self-mastery
so, that's where true will is born from
it manifests from
the understanding and interplay of the
higher self and all of creation, so, it's
the understanding of the self and the
understanding of
the forces that are at work in the
cosmos
both physical and spiritual, and
behavioral
laws
and the true will then once we
have developed that interplay, and we
have
begin to develop the true will
the true will, that path of action, will
guide us
those of us who will follow it, who will
actually
do
that action, meaning they they've come
into a place of wisdom
it will put you on
to your ultimate purpose in life
it will put you on to
the purpose that you manifested here for
and, see
i could say all day
yes
i'm bitter about
from a from an egoic point of view
from a personal point of view i'm bitter
i've done all of this work and the the
world is still completely enslaved
let's face it, i got a big chip on my
shoulder about it, from a personal point
of view
and i feel like i have that chip on my
shoulder, because i've tried been trying
to explain
to rock
hard heads out there
that you need to take action, it's not
good enough that you know any bit of
this, you can know every bit of this, and
it's useless, unless you yourself are
taking action based on it, because that's
the whole and all-encompassing
all-important word in this entire
exchange
if you don't understand that the true
will is action, it's not about anything
you want, it's not about what you know
it's not about what you feel inside, it's
about what are you
you
going to
do
what are you going to do
if you haven't answered that
question, and then made it happen
you're not doing the true will, you're
not on the path of the true will, you
have no real purpose, you're floating
through life effortless
not effortlessly, but you're floating
through life aimlessly
you don't have a clear... see, this is what
thelema helps with, it helps for one, for
the adherent, for the student
the practitioner, however you want to
look at that
to
develop a clear picture of what they
must do
when you really have a
firm grasp of the thelemic tradition, by
reading its documents, by studying it, by
really pondering what it means
not just even listening to the words
okay
this is a personal relationship
no one would then start asking the
question - oh, what can i do ? what should i
do ? i don't know what to do - that will be
gone - gone, gone, gone from you
and this is part of the problem
i think, because people don't go deeply
enough into esoteric knowledge and into
the world of the occult, and they think
all of this is bad
because some other fucking moron told
them - yeah, all the occult is bad, and you
shouldn't look in any of that
no, it's actually the most powerful
information on earth
in the cosmos, in general, that the
elitists don't want you to look at, so
you stay a stupid motherfucker
that's really how it works
so, once again
anybody's free to think of it however
you want - crowley was a satanist, i'm not
looking into thelema, fuck that
stay a dumb motherfucker then, stay
a purpose...
stay a purposeless person
floating through life aimlessly
and you're not going anywhere else
you're coming right back here, you're
gonna do it again, and again, and again
and again, until your hard head
fucking breaks like a rock
until the ego gets busted down into
powder
and then broken down even more and
nothing
you're coming back here
forever
until your hard head
decides
that it's the thing that is wrong and
needs to change
but you're free to believe whatever the
fuck you want and make that process as
painful as you want to make it
the universe will let you have that
you're not hurting anybody but yourself
ultimately, but
part of the problem is
because you're hurting other people that
actually do want to be free
with your ignorance
you know
willful ignorance does in the long term
harm others
so, going back to what i was saying
after i got thelema deeply
there's no more thinking what do you
need to do
you know what you need to do
and you start doing it
you're not asking questions about it
anymore, you're not dilly-dallying about
it, you get on it
you see
because you understand that you're here
to take action
not to go  me, not to go "what can i
do"
oh, i don't know how to do that
this tradition makes you confront
all your bullshit excuses, it makes you
confront your laziness, it tells you the
only one responsible for ultimately
either staying where you're at or
changing it is you, that's it
you are solely responsible
other people have influences in many
areas of life, of course, i'm not going to
say that they don't
but ultimately
if you're not part of the solution
you're part of the problem, if you're not
actively involved in taking action to
change it, you're the one helping anchor
it and to keep it there
you have to take action to make
a huge weight move
and, yeah, i get bitter, because i look at
i've been doing this for, you know
over 15 years
what has changed - hardly anything
there's some more people who are
beginning to grasp and understand the
great work and  do it themselves, yes
that's happening slowly
all too slowly, but it is happening
but when you get on this
personal path of action
it totally defines your purpose in life
and there's nothing better than living a
purpose-driven life
again, i could say i'm bitter, because i'd
rather, i'd quite rather
be free and have our lives to live as
we see fit, which is how it really should
be, that's the natural state of human
existence
anarchy
and freedom is the natural state of
human existence, having nobody rule
but because, unfortunately, there is
slavery
those of us who understand the wrongness
of that dynamic have to teach natural
law, i'm confined to this path, because of
other people's ignorance
i could get on a path of
wonderful self-expression and
exploration of other things that i want
to do
i've said many times i could have become
maybe
a musician, a painter, an inventor, who
knows
i think i have all of those things
inside of me
but i don't pursue them, because
i'm here on doing my true will, on my
personal
path of action that i know i must do, and
must be on
which is a constraint
and i do that of my free will, even
though, like i said, the lower aspect of
me can be bitter about and have a
fucking big chip on my shoulder about it
not going to lie
that's the dichotomy, but it's ultimately
unified, this is the idea in hermeticism
that
you know, opposites can ultimately be
unified
i'm still going to do it, i'm still going
gonna do the true will, because that's
what i'm charged with to do, it's a bond
it's a constraint
all things being equal meaning if we all
have unrestrained our natural rights
and they're not under attack
and they're not being
occultically
covertly
constrained and taken from human beings
by this occult priest class
if that were not the case
i'm not bound to do this, it would be a
good thing to have this be common sense
natural law
but pretty much if... if
the enslavement of humanity weren't the
problem, you could pretty much rest
assured natural law is commonplace in
that instance, in that scenario
see, when
decadence goes into place and corruption
goes into place
and evil
manifests like it has
that's when
the true will of
having to teach natural law
becomes a constraint, it becomes a bond
and i'm not saying that's a bad thing
i'm saying i do it out of my own free
will, because i know it must be done, it's
required, it's a requirement
that makes it a bond, it's like obtaining
food
it's a requirement, you're gonna have to
do it
so, that's a constraint, it's a boundary
condition
that's what law is - it's a boundary
it's a set of conditions that are in
place that have requirements must be
fulfilled, are always in place, are
constraining our binding
but one of the worst things that you
could ever have really happen is to lead
a purposeless life
to lead a life where
you don't know what your purpose is
or you don't even care what your purpose
is
and
let me tell you something, folks, there's
a ton of people in the world living like
that, a ton
just living with no purpose
so while on one hand "yes" i'll say
i could be bitter and have a chip on my
shoulder about having to do this work
non-stop
it absolutely fulfills purpose
it has given me a purpose-driven life
and that's one of the hardest things for
most people to find
how do you find what your purpose is to
do - thelema can help you discover that
it can help put you on that path, if you
understand it
let's continue
with more on the true will
those who are in touch with the true
will have eliminated or bypassed false
desires and internal contradictions
and have accessed a deep connection with
creation itself
once again, doing the true will
you could say - some people may
completely eliminate base desires
bypassing it or
keeping a handle on them - is one way of
saying it
where
i will still make the time to put
together a nice presentation like this, i
will still make the time to
have my talking points ready of what i
want to really discuss with people, make
the points, that i want to talk about and
flesh out
does that mean i can't ever do anything
of my own
in other time that i have during the
week ?
no, i could still go out and enjoy myself
go see music, go to a dinner, whatever
it doesn't mean that you're
put in a prison and living that
24-7, non-stop
but it means - you're making that your
life
this is what you're going to take a
portion of your life to do, to express to
other people, to teach, to communicate
most people just will not make it their
life, they will not make it a part of
their life, they just think, just...
i got, i heard it, i heard it, and i
understand it, and that's good enough
i'm basically a good person, i'm not
harming anybody and i understand what's
going on, it's still not enough
not reaching out to others means - you're
allowing the voice of evil to be louder
than everybody else, to be louder than
you
see, if there's evil taking place and
you're not speaking against it - you're
not doing the true will
you're not actively involved in
developing the true will
and you haven't conquered
to the extent that you need to do the
true will, those
desires, those contradictions within the
self
within the base self
see
it doesn't mean that someone
living the true will
has no base desires
it doesn't mean you live in an ascetic
monk-like lifestyle, okay, that's what you
have to understand - thelema is not that
no occult tradition is that, truly
those ascetic traditions are largely
eastern and some
middle eastern traditions, and they're
not
healthy, quite frankly
they're imbalanced, they're imbalanced
there are positions of extremity that
don't lead to good places, because you're
putting
one aspect of consciousness
spirituality over
another aspect of consciousness, which is
physicality
physicality and spirituality don't need
to be
seen as completely separate and never
between  concepts
as i teach in my work and as people, who
really understand real spirituality, have
taught, they're one and the same
it's all consciousness
the body is part of that, the physical
world is part of that, matter is part of
that
so, you don't need to
forever exterminate desires
it's not to say, you're not going to have
base flesh, flesh worldly
selfish desires, ever
you're not going to live for them
to the extent
that you will not get involved in the
great work
you're not going to be controlled by
them to the extent
that you're not going to teach natural
law, that you're not going to speak out
against evil
personally
it's
you know
the idea that
you could fulfill
based desires
from time to time
and
not be perfect, no one's gonna be perfect
it's, again, this isn't about leading a
monk-like ascetic lifestyle for the rest
of your life, no one's asking that or
even saying that's a good idea, again, i
think it's a
place of extremity, and
bad extremity, and
imbalance in consciousness
but what i'm trying to get at here in
the true will is that
you
keep those things in check
to the point where you are making
the doing of the great work
an absolute part of your existence
and i personally don't feel that there's
any excuse for people not to do that
i think that we live in the type of
culture and settings largely here in
what you would call the first world
western civilization
who are the people i'm largely speaking to
we have
the resources
the information, we have the connectivity
we have the time, even, where we can
dedicate a certain portion of our life
to this work
and that is
the beginning of the activation of the
true will
and then, in the second sentence here i'm
saying
as more human beings discover and
achieve this state of consciousness
meaning the alignment with the true will
and and beginning to do that
accessing that deep connection with
creation
the more
as more human beings discover and
achieve that state of consciousness
the more human life will flow without
resistance in the
aggregate
again, this is the law of freedom
in
thelemic terms they call this the law
of liberty
crowley said that
the
liberty of human beings or the...
he expressed it as - the control
of the state will be a function of
the attainment to liberty of each
human will, i'm paraphrasing, but
basically, it's like
as people are
doing their true will
more and more
the state and the controllers will have
less power
and more freedom will manifest in the
world
it's a function of the individual will
i'll see, if i could even find the phrase
give me a moment, because it's worth
putting up here into the presentation
i'll actually add it in, during the show
but this second sentence is what i'm
saying
it's what i call the law of freedom
as more human beings are doing this true
will, doing the one great work, teaching
natural law, teaching objective morality
life will flow with less resistance
we will actually begin to get what we
want, when we do the will of creation
instead of our selfish wills, as we
become more moral and teach objective
morality
and spread objective morality, humanity
becomes more free, as we refuse to do
that, and don't care about objective
morality, and let
tyrons take over - humanity becomes more
and more enslaved
as people will not speak out against
tyranny
as they will not
say
what is wrong and why to other people
expect more tyranny to encroach, expect
freedom to be curtailed
more and more, expect more slavery
as morality increases - freedom increases
as morality declines - freedom declines
not speaking out is a form of immorality
when faced with tyranny, when faced with
slavery, to say nothing is an act of
immorality in and of itself
let me just say that again, folks
when confronted with tyranny and slavery
not to speak using your voice
to say definitively the wrongness of
that state of existence
is
immorality in and of itself
not to take action in that circumstance
is a form of immorality
you are being complicit with the tyranny
by not using your voice to speak out
against it and speak truth to that form
of
absolute immoral power
i apologize for the background noise
folks, i can't control that what's going
on outside, hopefully that's not coming
through too much over the broadcast, but
it's a warm day here in philadelphia, i
do have
the windows open and i have the fan on
in here, so
if there is a little bit of background
noise i apologize for that, there's a dog
constantly barking outside
and it's kind of distracting to me
but anyway
i think, i've explained the true will to
my satisfaction, so, i'm going to move on
the phrase "do what thou wilt shall be
the whole of the law" is a huge
expression
in the thelemic philosophy, you hear it
over and over again
and people use this phrase completely
incorrectly, don't know what they're
talking about, to insist that
this is a satanic ideology
and thelema is basically
satanism because it's saying "do whatever
the hell you want, there's no consequence
there's no law, do whatever you want"
wrong
percent
1000 percent
1 million percent - wrong
absolutely incorrect, if you think that
you don't know what the fuck you're
talking about
and yet every single solitary day i hear
some other fucking chump
say
"oh
thelema, do what thou wilt, that's
satanism, do whatever you want"
you don't know what the fuck you're
talking about, and i have to just say it
that way, i got it, i just got to come in
strong, just like that, just to get it
right out there confrontationally
first
you're wrong
that's not what it is
that's not what it means, yes, you're
wrong
it's not correct, it isn't true, you're
let's get that
first and foremost, out in the open, very
clear
and i've said this
ad nauseam amount of times, and people
will still
insist - "no, i'm right, that's satanism"
no, you're a dunce
you don't read
you don't understand, you don't have
discernment, i do
i'm correct
see
sometimes people just have to be told
like a little fucking child
unfortunately
because it's so blatantly out there in
all the information that a child could
go look it up
and find the incorrectness of
the
contention that
"do what thou wilt" means "do whatever you
want", and that means "thelema is satanism"
a fucking four-year-old can go find the
contradiction to that
that that isn't true
that's how much availability of
information there is in that regard
regarding this philosophy
and people don't do it
they just roll by what they heard, by
what somebody else told them
that they know nothing about from a
first-hand perspective, because they
haven't actually downloaded the material
and fucking read it
maybe that's where people should start
with anything
is downloading the source material and
reading it
god forbid
that involves an investment of time
and effort
we can't have that
can't have that
you gotta make a quick snap judgment on
what some other fucking idiot said, you
don't know that ?
that's how we roll in the 21st century
boy
we don't read
so, let's explain
to the hard heads out there what "do what
thou wilt shall be the whole of the law"
really means
as this dog barks incessantly during the
entirety of my podcast today
one of the main precepts of thelema is
"do what thou wilt shall be the whole of
the law"
this phrase
is almost...
is almost always
completely misunderstood and taken out
of context
understood correctly
this most certainly does not mean "do
whatever you want", in a purely selfish
context
"do what thou wilt shall be the whole of
the law" refers to the true will
which we just talked about, was an
alignment of one's personal path of
action in life to higher universal
spiritual natural law
meaning if you align one's
own will with the will of creation - that
is the whole will of the law, that is the
whole of the law
that is ultimately what
the expression of natural law and the
intelligence, the intelligent ordering
force
of justice in the cosmos, is attempting
to achieve
and it's what it wants
us to do with our lives to find that
purpose, and walk that path of action
express it through our behaviors
"do what thou wilt shall be the whole of
the law" refers to the true will, one's
wholly aligned spiritual path in life
upon which we are guided once we have
learned to hear and follow the higher
self, again, in thelema
the true will
and
"doing what thou wilt" meaning "doing the
true will", not the selfish will
see, "do what thou wilt" capital "w"-will
would be
symbolically and allegorically expressed
as the magus card of the thoth tarot
deck, crowley's own personal tarot deck
that he appointed to be paint
this is the magician card in the
traditional tarot deck
crowley refers to it as the magus
which is
latin for magician
and
you know, you could see he has the 4
elements there
and then
the 5th element
expressed as
his crown chakra exploding with the
serpentine energy
up to the grail and
the wings of ma'at
a lot of
alchemical symbolism, a lot of egyptian
symbolism in
crowley's thoth deck
you see, then the
baboon creature
in the background there, reaching up to
try to reach the magus and, maybe
possibly pull him down from his
perch there
and that represents our base desires
which we have to tame, they're always
there, they're not gone
permanently
but we keep them under control
and
we don't allow them to pull us down from
that path that we are walking, which is
that thin straight line, that the magus
is on
it's beautiful symbolism, if it's
understood, if it's not understood - people
go - "oh, it's a guy standing there with
like a cop, and a dagger", and
yeah, they don't, they don't grasp what
they're seeing
because this is what people who aren't
literate in occult symbolism do, they see
things at just face value and they have
no idea what any of this represents
you know, you have
swords, wands, cups and coins, the 4
suits of the tarot, the 4 alchemical
elements
coins representing earth
resources
bodily characteristics etcetera
we have the intellect represented by
the sword
or the dagger
in this case
the wand
the cup representing of our emotions
our emotional intelligence and heart
based intelligence
and then, of course, the
wand representing the will
fire
so, air would be the intellect, the dagger
water - the cup, obviously
which holds water
representing the emotions
and then fire, the wand, which is action
we broke that down pretty extensively
when we covered tarot
and the
4 suits of the tarot deck, like the
4 suits of the playing card, playing
card deck
and the magus wields
all of these tools
because he's
attained self-mastery over the base
desires to walk the path of the true
will
and be the servant of creation, and
fulfill natural law
hence
"do what thou wilt is the whole of the
law"
brilliant symbolism
i like how he puts the baboon creature
in there to represent
the base desires aren't
going anywhere, they're still
there
we have to achieve
ownership over them
and not let them own us
i
like some of the things that someone
like jordan peterson says, i wouldn't say
he has a
total understanding, especially not of
the occult
philosophies out there and
definitely, doesn't understand the power
structure of the world as it truly
exists
but one thing he said is
that i liked which
talked about this, restraining of the
base instincts
he has a quote out there, that says
a good man
he says
a man who
isn't dangerous - isn't a good man, you
know, a truly good man is a very
dangerous man, who has it
under his voluntary control
i may be paraphrasing slightly, but
essentially that's it
a truly good man
is actually a very dangerous man
has the potential for great
destructive behavior, great violent
behavior or self-defensive behavior, if
you would
but he's keeping that under his
voluntary control
that potential danger, that he represents
that's actually always a potential
let's move on
and, you know, just let me step back for a
moment, the part that
we're guided on the path of the will
toward our purpose
once we've learned to hear and follow
the higher self, again, that is
what's made possible through meditative
tantric
breathing
yogic practices etcetera
and there's many other methods
psychedelics could be one, if you do it
properly
some people would consider them
shortcuts, some people see them as tools
in a different sense
but that voice doesn't speak above a
whisper
our chatter is yapping away at a million
miles an hour at top volume
in our minds
you know
it's the thing where
like
you really ask people what they believe
and they say some of the most
contradictory nonsensical things about
what they believe is going on, happening
what they need to do, when you just sit
them down and say
"really be in the room with that thought
really focus on it
sit in front of the mirror, and tell it
to yourself
like you're trying to get the other
image to believe you
and you'll realize how full of shit
most of us are all day, every day
every second of the day"
this is what these practices
that are part of thelemic practices are
about
it's about having that conversation with
the self, and really have the
conversation - "am i doing what i'm
supposed to be doing ?
am i a coward ? am i on the path and do i
have really have a purpose in life ? am i
fulfilling it ?"
i can honestly sit there and say
i've asked myself those questions, i've
had the conversation in the mirror over
and over, and over, and over, and over
again
i've conquered
to the extent, that they're not owning me
those base desires, and fears, and
contradictions, not to do the
the great work
not to get on the path of the true will
and i'm truly on it, i could say it
honestly, i can answer that honestly
how many people can ?!
most people, you are
constantly lying to yourself, you're
constantly saying bullshit to yourself
and trying to get your ego to believe it
and most people will pick it up and go
"yeah, that's true, oh, yeah, yeah
i believe that, i can buy into that"
see, it often takes somebody confronting
you with your own bullshit for you to
even hear what you're telling yourself
you know
it's part of the problem, is that most
people don't have anybody that will do
that
people don't want to create
confrontative scenarios, they don't like
being in that state where "oh, my god, he
just said something that really hits home"
people have done it to me in the past
and it's been an uncomfortable situation
and, guess what, if it's true i look into
it and change, if it's not true
then
i'll say
that's your opinion and that's your
advice
but there is a difference between
being true or not
make no mistake about it
has nothing to do whether you like what
you're hearing or not
and, see, that's part of the practices of
thelema, when you research them look
into them
do them yourself
they get you to sit there with those
thoughts and weed them out
weed out the inconsistencies, weed out
the contradictions
it you eventually have a
conversation with yourself where you're
telling yourself how much bullshit
you've believed, you've told
yourself that
nobody else even had to tell you - you're
eager to tell yourself a handful bullshit and believe it
and "do what thou wilt shall be the whole
of the law" is part of
breaking that ego down
see, it's getting to hear that voice that
never speaks above a whisper
that is the connection to higher self
you got to get the other chatter out of
the mind, and there's techniques for that
for those called to the path of the true
will
it refers to the one great work of truth
love and freedom, that is what the true
will ultimately refers to
the true will is to align oneself with
higher will - what does the higher will of
creation want for all of its creatures ?
it wants
people to be free, it wants people to be
happy, it wants freedom from suffering
that is not
self and that is self-inflicted
obviously there's going to be some forms
of suffering contained in life, again, the
buddhist tradition talks about that, and
that's a big part of thelema, it mixes
some of the eastern traditions in with
the western mystery traditions
it's a very aggregate tradition, a
tradition with
which
coalesces a lot of other
mystical traditions and occult
traditions
buddhism is a big one
which one of the main tenets of buddhism
is that life contains suffering, or
a better way of saying it is
suffering is contained within life
the the buddhists teachings
never
anywhere in the original teachings of
buddhism
say "life is suffering", this is a total
total bastardization of the buddhist
tradition, which is a huge part of the
thelemic tradition
never anywhere
was it ever written or said
"life is suffering"
that is a bullshit new age and or
dark buddhist variant of the phrase
"suffering exists within life
suffering is contained within life
life contains suffering", it has suffering
within it
by its very essence, by its inherent
nature
living will
contain within it
certain aspects of suffering that one
must endure
and what that ultimately means is - some
forms of suffering are self-generated
some are not self-generated
but the overwhelming bulk majority of
suffering is self-generated, and if we
learn how not to create that suffering
we won't experience it
it will be alleviated from us, that's the
the path of buddhism and
noble path etcetera
you have the noble truths and then
the noble paths
and, you know, one of the noble truths is
there is a method for not generating
those forms of self-inflicted suffering
and then the path shows you how to do
that
very similar to the thelemic path
to get on the path of the true will is
to begin
ceasing creating that self-inflicted
suffering by doing the great work of
teaching natural law, and teaching
objective morality, so, that it becomes
common sense
and that is you being a servant to truth
love and freedom
instead of doing whatever you want
and being a coward
and not talking out against evil and
tyranny
continuing with this paragraph
"do what thou wilt" in a thelemic context is literally the exact opposite of
the phrase "do whatever you want"
literally
dipoles, diametrically opposed opposites
nothing to do with each other, over here
is "do what thou wilt shall be the whole
of the law", over here is "do whatever you
want", and never the twain shall meet
complete opposites of each other
for anybody who truly understands it
for imbecile assholes, who don't know
what the fuck they're talking about, and
who insists thelema is something that
it is not
they want to
make them equivalents, which they are not
they're exactly extreme opposites of
each other
"do what thou wilt" is the apotheosis of
freedom
so, i'm continuing this sentence from the
one before, "do what thou wilt" in a
thelemic context is literally the exact
opposite of "do whatever you want", it is
the apotheosis of freedom, that means... "do
what thou wilt" means
because you are serving creation's will
and because ultimately that will is for
the freedom of all
for true freedom to manifest and for
every being to be sovereign
it is the elevation
of freedom to the position of godhood
that's what apotheosis means - elevation
to godhood
and, indeed, that is what truth, love and
freedom are - that is what god is
god is truth, god is love, god is freedom
and ultimately all 3 of those things
together
is natural law, god is law
that's... the law is the boundary
condition, you could call it
symbolically, represent that as a circle
and then put an equilateral triangle in
it - truth, love, freedom, again, that is why
the all-seeing eye design is what it is
that's why i use it in the one great
work
and one great work network, and what on
earth is happening
sell t-shirts with it on it etcetera
that's why it is the little
icon of the one great work network
because the boundary condition is
natural law that's, the circle, and then
truth, love, and freedom
are what it is
bringing into manifestation in the
physical world
that is the godhood
truth, love, freedom, there are the
expressions of it in the physical, hence
the triangle is the basic
you know
geometry of nature
and the circle
is the perfected shape that represents
the the construct
represents the
underlying ordering intelligence, that is
the creator
"do what thou wilt"
is the apotheosis of freedom and the
strictest possible bond, this is what i
talked about before, it's a constraint
it's the law
okay, that's what natural law is
and that's the bond
okay, you're bonded to that in life
meaning, it's not really an option
you know that end times that are not
equal like what we're living in a state
of slavery
you must
do this type of work
the true will doesn't have to be that
let's say, we were living on a planet
where everyone's rights were respected
everybody knew natural law, everybody
knew objective morality and align their
behavior to it
let's say, almost everybody, you're still
going to have
strayers from the path, it's
gonna  to happen
but, let's say, we dealt with that in a
natural law capacity
meaning, we just took care of it
we don't build prisons
we don't constrain other people's rights
we just take care of the problem, that's
how it would be done in a natural law
society
you could call that brutality, if you
want, but, guess what, it would cleanse the
place of those disruptor agents
that want to try to get their hooks in
and convert other people to their
misery and low consciousness
mindset
you know that's exactly what it's like
people in that deranged state of mind of
wanting to be controllers, it's been
likened like a sick person on a
being carried on on a gurney, and
attacking all the people that are
holding him up on
the
thing that they're carrying them on to
get him to a hospital
that's what they do, the sick then
attacks and make harms other people and
makes them tries to make them like him
that's what the whole
dark occult mindset is and does, that's
what the psychopath is and does
so, if we lived on a place that...
in a place that already understood
natural law, and we didn't have to worry
about the total
destruction of our rights
and we essentially lived every day with
our rights intact, the true will would
not have to be
doing this work all the time
you would have this work out there
naturally in the course of the knowledge
of the people of the planet
it would have to be that way for that
condition to manifest in the first place
so, then, hey, what if i wanted to become a
master sculptor ?
i could turn my will over to that, that
could be my path in life, that may be my
purpose to express beauty and
potentiality of what a human being could
do in something like that
maybe, i want to invent some new piece
of technology
and that could be my true will
so, when i say at a time
when all things are equal
again, when they're not equal
and we're living as if some people are
gods and other people are their slaves
like we are now
the true will of
just about everyone
is constrained
it's a bond, it gets bound up
and it all comes together
where
you don't have that potentiality to say
"i'm going to go be that master sculptor
or that master painter, or that master
musician, or that master inventor"
if you simply go and then follow that
path - that's not the true will
because the true will has to align with
one's...
with the will of creation
on a planet, where
rights are intact
someone going inventing something new to
help bring higher expressions of
consciousness potentiality
the development of the species to
higher
levels of complexity etcetera
would be the will of creation
for a planet, whose people don't
understand rights, don't understand what
a right is, what a wrong is, what natural
law is
why we shouldn't be enslaving each other
why there shouldn't be government at all
for a planet that ignorant
the true will
of all
is to first get that planet and all the
people on it to that base level of
understanding of
morality and natural law
so
where we're at now on this planet
that we call earth
which is a hell world
it has devolved into a hell world
there really is only one true will
because to follow any other path than
the one that would create truth, love
freedom
is to go against the will of creation
and, i can say, i understand that, i can
say, that's a true statement, most people will
say "oh, that's what you think"
no, it's what i've come to understand
if you just give it some thought, quietly
alone, and really deeply contemplate it
you'll understand
right now
not to do the true will
of the one great work
is literally telling creation
to go of itself
as jordan maxwell said
you are screwing with cosmic justice
and screwing with cosmic justice is only
going to bring anybody, that does that
one thing - cosmic judgment
again, that's the law of freedom
not teaching morality and natural law in
a place where we're already enslaved
is complicity with the evil, that's
already in control here
that's why so many people's lives can't
flow effortlessly
and there's so little prosperity
in most people's lives
because we've let such injustice and
iniquities, and evil breed everywhere all
around us
largely unchallenged running a muck
you think the universe is going to
give us what we say, we want selfishly ?
with the lower case will, "w", lowercase "w"
will
when we're not serving the higher case "w"
and
people think we deserve anything better
than what we have ? they think, they
personally deserve anything better than
what they have
that's the exact reason we're in this
place
is because so many people selfishly
choose to do what they want to do for
themselves, because it's more comfortable
because they don't really want freedom
they don't really want truth, they don't
really want love, they want what they
want for themselves
which is being a selfish prick
that's called being a selfish prick
that's not doing the one great work
that's not doing the true will
certainly not advancing the will of
creation
it's advancing the selfish will of the
individual
once again, i have a selfish will
everybody does - who doesn't ?
wonderful - who cares ?
that's like saying somebody, you know, has
an anus, everybody does
you know, everybody's got a mouth
the whole point is
that doesn't make you unique
getting a handle on that, so, that it
doesn't control you, will make you unique
that'll put you on the path
to mastery
and, again, it's not about being perfect
it's not about leading an ascetic
lifestyle, when you shun every pleasure
by no means is that my life
it means you make doing the true will
you make doing the one great work
the most important aspect of your life
and everything is secondary to it
because if you're not doing that you're
not living a purpose-driven life and
you're certainly not fulfilling your
true will
especially, on a planet that is as fucked
up as this one
to go and just turn away from doing that
will and go live your selfish will
really, really does put you in a bad
karmic place
and in a terrible position as a human
being
and you still can't get people to
understand that, they're still going to
live their selfish lives, their selfish
ways, because they're ignorant, they're
apathetic
they're cowardly, and they're lazy - the
four murderers of consciousness
ignorance, apathy, laziness, cowardice
they have such an abundance of one or
all of them
one or more or all of those murderers of
consciousness that they cannot come out
of that lower state of consciousness
something
in some form of trauma is holding them
there
it's like a weight on top of
them, it's like something that has them
it's like a cage
we're going to talk about the head cage
a little bit later in this presentation
and that is what's binding them
they're not bound to
creation's law, they're not bound to
truly "do what thou wilt"
they're letting
that baboon creature, there in the
background, bind them
the selfish desire, the ignorance
the laziness
big time the cowardice, it's a big one
that stops everybody
i don't want to put my voice out there
i don't want to put a target on myself, i
don't want other people to see me, i
don't want other people to hear me
just so much
fucking fear
it's pathetic
it's fucking pathetic
and, you know what ? the bigger fear that
they really should be focused on is
what they're actually doing to their
soul
at a cosmic level
by not getting involved
and, again, i could say this forever and
ever, and ever, until the end of time
and there are people who are still going
to just say - fuck it, i don't care, i'm not
going to do it
that's your soul
that's on your soul, no one else, that's
on you and your soul
and, believe me
you
will
definitively
deal with that at some point
you may not deal with it in the flesh
and in the physical, but you're
gonna
deal with it, you will be
forced
by the universe to deal with that, and
confront that
and i don't really understand people's
fear like that, it makes no sense to
me... i'm not in that mindset
thankfully, it's one of the things i have
a lot of gratitude about, i would never
want to be that person, again, i look at
it in the
example, allegorically, of, you know, the
the movie they made about the
greek demigod, achilles
allegedly the greatest warrior of the
the greeks
who's gonna go into battle against the
enemies of the greek empire
and
he's getting ready to go into battle, i
think, possibly against persian armies
and
in the movie achilles
a child
maybe a teenager age, says to him - aren't
you afraid ?
and he goes - no, i'm not afraid
and, because he knows what he has to do
he knows the forces he has to confront
he knows, he has to go into battle, and
it's an allegory to go into
spiritual battle
and he says - no, i am not afraid
and the the kid, he's talking with the
boy, says
if i was going to be fighting that army
i'd be very afraid
and achilles looks at him right in the
face as a small child, as a, you know
young
boy
and he says directly to him
that is why no one will ever remember
your name
and it's not in an egoic sense of "i want
to go down in the annals of history and
have my name remembered" - it's not that
that's not the ego place, he's saying
that from
he's saying - that's why you won't be a
truly great person
you won't be anyone that anybody wants
to ever talk about and remember, once
you're dead your name will be forgotten
forever, it will pass like a snap of a
fingers from the living systemic memory
of creation, you won't be anything
you will be remembered as nothing
because
you didn't do great things
because your fear held you back from
doing what is right and what is great
and what is true and what is good
that's the allegorical
aspect that achilles in the movie is
saying that to the child, i should play
it, i should download it and play it
maybe i'll do that, i'd like to
you know, maybe add that jordan peterson
quote the exact wording of it, i want to
add that quote from crowley about the
will of the state, i should have put that
in the presentation
maybe i'll do that after the slide, i'll
just download a couple of things, maybe
we can read from a couple of thelemic
writings, as well, but i want to get
through the philosophy, so
continuing with this
"do what thou wilt
shall be the whole of the law" is the
apotheosis of freedom and the strictest
possible bond in crowley's own words "do
thy will and no other shall say nay", once
again, that goes back to what we talked
about in the last part of this slide, in
the last paragraph
that if we are doing the true will
especially in the aggregate
universal forces come to our aid and
human life begins to flow effortlessly
without resistance
that is what "do thy will and no other
shall say nay" means
radio host...
his name is slipping my mind
used to say - be bold and mighty forces
will come to your aid
very similar to this phrase "do thy will
and no other shall say nay"
jack blood, i think, his name was, yes, jack
blood
be bold and mighty forces will come to
your aid
"do thy will and no other shall say nay"
that's it
courage
it requires courage
i should put the strength card up
for that, as well, because that's the
strength card from the thoth deck is a
huge aspect of thelema, the
development of courage
cowardice stops so many from the true
will, from the true spiritual path
they can't get over
something, there's something in them
that's incomplete
there's some part of themselves that
doesn't love themselves
you know, i won't let fear stop me, that
doesn't matter to me, because
if you know that your consciousness is
infinite
what's dying here going to do, transition
the consciousness from one form to
another
so what ?
it's probably happened to us millions of
times already
more likely than not
continuing with
"do what thou wilt shall be the whole of
the law" - is one of the precepts or tenets
of thelema
to aligns one life
with the true will
is to work toward the state of true
freedom for all
to focus largely upon selfish desires
and
you know, you could say not even focusing
on those desires, but letting those base
desires and or instincts like cowardice
like trauma
hold you back from doing that great work
from being on the path of the true will
is the same thing as
letting that
baboon creature
still have hold of you, and to take you
off the path
to focus largely upon selfish desires
and or let... cowardice get
the better of you
will ensure that obstacles arise for you
in every aspect of life, every aspect of
life
what your purpose is
where you want to be, who you want to be
around
relationships
resources etcetera, they will all
have resistance
there will be something that will fight
you, every step of the way, unless you're
really on the path that you're supposed
to be on
every act we conduct that is not in
harmony with the true will
is erratic
and will act as a hindrance in our lives
both at an individual level and at a
collective level
once again, the individual wills are
comprising ultimately the behavior of
the collective of the aggregate
and as aggregate morality goes, as the
quality of aggregate behavior
either in harmony with objective
morality or out of alignment with it
goes, that's how the whole aggregate of
society goes, and then we get the result
order or chaos, freedom or slavery, good
or evil
it's really not that hard to figure out
folks, if you know the basics of natural
law
and if this is just different wording
again, kabbalah just different wording
same ideas
freemasonry - different wording, different
symbols, different rituals - same idea
rosicrucianism - different wording
different nomenclature, different symbols
same idea
there's nothing new under the sun
you see
that's what that really means
you're not learning anything new here
if you weren't familiar with thelema
but you were familiar with
true freemasonry - it's one and the same
if you weren't familiar with thelema
but you really have a firm grasp
of natural law - it's one and the same
there's nothing new
in thelema there is a concept of higher
love
and this is referred to as "agape"
the greek word "agape" written there in
greek letters
alpha gamma alpha pi eta, and, again
"agape" pronounced
"agapE", it's not "agApe"
or "agapI"
right
so, thelema is spelled with that eta
before the mu alpha, at the end
theta epsilon lambda eta mu alpha, agape
is spelled
alpha gamma alpha pi
eta, how do you pronounce agape
you don't say Agapi
you wouldn't say thelima
it's thelema
the eta is a long "ei" sound in classical
greek
that's not in question
so, the correct pronunciation is agape
just like the correct pronunciation is
thelema
and this refers to true love, so, you have
true will
not lowercase "w"-will, but
big "w"-will
agape
is
big uppercase "l"-love
not the other forms of love, the
lower case "l"-love
agape is true love
which is a different expression of love
from romantic, familial, or even brotherly
or platonic love
in the greek language different forms of
love were given different words
the word eros
transliterated in english e-r-o-s in
greek it's epsilon
rho
omicron
sigma, final sigma, eros meant...
means romantic love, that is the
love between man and woman, between
partners, life partners etcetera, whether they
be
man-woman, man-man, woman-woman
doesn't matter gender, it's not about
physical gender, eros is
life partner romantic love
physical love
and then the word philos
transliterated p-h-i-l-o-s, where we get
the root from the word philadelphia
right, love of brother, philos
delphos
right, which is
love brother, brotherly love, the city of
brotherly love
the word philos in greek written
phi
iota
lambda
omicron
final sigma
and, actually i should put the final
sigma, that's not the final sigma, let me
try to
write that in there the way it's
supposed to
it's still not coming out, no...
now, i have to put that in there correctly
because at the end of the word i don't
believe it should have that, it should
have the regular
final sigma-s
give me a moment, i want to correct that
while i'm doing this, actually
this way, i don't forget when i put the
slides out
so, just give me one moment to correct
that
i'll keep explaining it while i'm doing
this
you know
philos is
love of
people
it's love of family
it's
you know, basic
platonic love
as separate from romantic love
i think, i have the
character, that i want now
it's not the right
it's not the right font, just give me one
more moment, and i'll correct this
but these other two forms of love
eros and philos, is not
what we are referring to
when we talk about
a higher expression of love
that comes from higher consciousness
these are forms of love that we express
toward people
right
so, in a romantic relationship
eros would be expressed
in
a family
philos is expressed, or between just
friends
you know
you'd be expressing
philos
platonic love
i still can't find the character, so, i'll
probably have to just let that go and
fix it on my own time, i'll have to look
at a
program that will allow me to get that
character set correct, because when i
typed it in, it transliterated it from
english
and it didn't give me the final s
i need another program to do
that
and i don't have it installed here
so
yeah, that's not going to be possible for
me to do on the air, unfortunately, so, i'm
going to step back into the slides and
let the
error be there
where i should have the final sigma
instead of the regular sigma
but i will fix it before i put the
slides out tomorrow
so, agape on the other hand means love
that comes from a higher state of
consciousness
it is love of all beings, it is
the desire for all beings to be free
in their rights, free, not in bondage, not
in slavery, and
for the desire for all beings to be free
of suffering
to the extent that that is possible
agape is universal love, some people call
it unconditional love, i personally don't
really like that term, because that means
there are
if it's universal - there's
no real conditions applied to it, but to
word it as earthly unconditional love
means, like you'll keep loving somebody
even if they're evil, and it doesn't mean
that, that's not what it refers to
if you look up agape you'll get a lot of
the christian tradition, because they use
the word in many christian traditions, as
well
to mean
unconditional christ-like love
i would say agape is similar to that, but
i personally would not use the word
unconditional
because that makes people think in two
physical terms of you'll apply this
mentality, no matter how evil what
someone is doing is, and that's not
really what it
actually, technically means
i like the term universal love, it is
love that extends beyond all boundaries
in that sense it's unconstrained
it
isn't... to people it is the love of truth
and freedom themselves
it's the love of what is right
it's the love of justice
okay, so, it's the love that binds
together truth and freedom in the
equation truth-love-freedom
okay
that is ultimately what agape is, and
that's what we're talking about when we
talk about agape and, of course, i put the
lovers card there to represent that
let's move on
and talk a little bit about
gematria or
occult numerology
it's huge in thelema, and crowley
really, really, really
applied gematria to a lot of what he did
he encoded
symbolically
words and concepts
in number
in
many of the writings that he did, in book
titles
in concepts and books, in many cases just
straight out rodent number
and
in studying thelema you're going to come
across
numerology for certain
so
let's look at what gematria actually is
in just any form of occultism, but
especially
thelemic numerology
so, in
thelema gematria is a form of occult
numerology
in gematria in general
the letters of words are converted to
numeric value
so, let's say, my name mark in english
gematria
right
so
you could put up an english gematria
table like "m" has a value, i believe, it's
13, right
let me, actually, just look it up real
quick
so
and i have
a bad spelling here, let me fix that
gematria has one "m"
i spelled it wrong a couple times here
okay
i think i got it fixed, no, it's spelled
wrong there
okay
doing all kinds of editing
so
here's an english... well, i'm looking at
an english gematria table
and
"m"
is 13, but then you reduce the "m" to 4
because you add the 1 and the 3 in
so, the second letter of my name is "a"
that's 1
first letter of the english alphabet
so, if we add the 4
and the 1 together - we have 5
then "r"
"r" is
in the english alphabet
18th letter
the 1 and the 8 add together to form 9
a 9 as we will see acts as a zero
but we can add it together with what we
have so far - 4,1,9
right
so that's 14
and we add that together - we're back to
5, which is what 1 and 4 are
so, that's how the 9 is a zero
we're going to see this in a couple
moments
how 9s are always zeros
but
let's go to the "k" now, "k" is 2
because it is
it's the 11th letter of the english
alphabet, 1 and 1 is 2
so, we add that together
right
4, 1, 9 and 2
1 plus 6 is 7
so, my first name "mark"
in english gematria
is a 7
that's how you do reduction in gematria
so
we're going to do gematria on the word
thelema
and find its value in greek gematria
on the next slide
let's look at some classical occult
gematria
the number 666
depicted at the bottom of this table, on
the left
always represented incompletion
6 and 7
in numerology
in the occult world are
incomplete and complete
6 is incomplete, 7 is complete
8 is perfect
and 9 would represent
total union
but, also, in
a different aspect
nothing
union to the point of completion versus
zero
and you could look at that as coming
full circle
666 always represented
base consciousness
incompletion in thought, emotion and
action, if we ascribe
one letter of the
trinity of
of numbers
to one to each aspect of consciousness
thought
being in a state of
incompletion or imbalances
ignorance
emotion, being in a state of
incompleteness, non-achievement, would be
apathy
and our actions remaining in a state of
incompleteness is
cowardice and laziness, that which stops
you from taking
right real world action
that is what 666 has meant in different
occult numerological traditions, man in
base consciousness, the beast
in thelema you'll hear the term "the
great beast", you know
or "therion"
"megatherion"
"the great beast"
it's a reference to the beast of
revelation
but ultimately that 666 is the number of
man
you know
in
the book of revelation that's what it is
said - it is the number of man, not of a
man, but of man
meaning that man is in that incomplete
state, humanity is in that incomplete
state, meaning mankind
thought, emotion and action in
an incomplete inactive and contradictory
state
so, then do the gematria reduction, 6
plus 6, plus 6 is 18
1 plus 8 is 9, you just
keep
adding them together
that's all you're doing in reduction
it's very simple, people try to make it
more
complex than it really is, gematria
reduction means adding together
the individual values of letters in a
word repeatedly, until a single new
numerical value is reached, for example
777, which is the next one we could do
representing man and unity consciousness
the thoughts, emotions and actions are
complete, they're activated, they're
unified, there's no contradiction
it's intelligence
it's true care, true love
and, then, true will
which is right action
courage
right action
very simple
concepts, representing consciousness, but
then expressed through number, to encode
them, to encode it
because at times and places you couldn't
teach this you could be murdered for
teaching it, you could be tortured for
teaching it
and, so, people have come up with
ingenious encoding systems including the
tarot, including occult
gematria, including allegorical stories
etcetera
so, 777 - do the reduction
7 plus 7, plus 7 is 21
2 plus 1 is 3, that's the
reduction of 777
so, in thelemic gematria it is generally
accepted that words which reduce to the
same numerical value actually share the
same meaning
and my slides are fraught with error
today, but that's okay, we'll fix them on
the fly
so
anywhere you would see 777 - you could say
that's equivalent to 3
gematria wise
so, 3 would represent man in unity
consciousness, again, the trinity
thought, emotion and action
body, mind, spirit
father, son
spirit
or father, mother, son
ultimately the
mother is the heart, the spirit of that
equation, and then the divine child
allegorically is right action, so, it's a
male aspect
in the father-mother
male-child
son trinity
and 9 would be
the reduction of 666, which means it has
the same
meaning
base consciousness
adds no value, anything you add a nine to
doesn't change the value, as we just saw
we had are already five
"m" and "a" - "m" is 4 in english germatria, "a"
is 1 - that's 5, add the 9
14 - 1 plus 4 is 5
no change, because you already had 4
and 1 - 5
any number you add 9 to
you could just do it
so, add it to the 3 for an example
1 plus 2 - 3, you're back to 3
let's take the 7
add the 9
16 - 1 plus 6
as the reduction back to 7
adding 9 is adding zero, so, anywhere
in a gematria reduction, if you see a
9 - just cross it out, don't add it
because it's a zero
gematria wise, it's a zero
numerology wise, it doesn't add value
because it represents unconsciousness, it
represents deadness, it represents being
totally in
base
ego identified consciousness
which adds no value, you can't change
anything with it, you can't change value
for the greater with the 9, you see
it's something i've been explaining
numerologically why it's a a brilliant
understanding, you can't add
666 to anything and change its value, try
to do it, start with seven
add 666
666 is 18
right
okay
18 plus 7 is 25
2 plus 5 from the 25 is
7, you're back to 7, 666 is a
zero
in gematria terms
so, what 666 represents is
base consciousness that can change
nothing, it can't add any value, just like
9 can't add any value, when you
multiply anything by 9
you get more of 9
times 2 is 18
1 plus 8 is 9, you're back to
9 times 3 is 27
2 plus 7 is 9, you're back to
9 times 6 is 54
5 plus 4
is 9
9 times 7 is 63, 6 plus
3 is 9 - anything you multiply by
nine
you only get more of 9
multiplying base consciousness gets you
more base consciousness
it's just like a brilliant
conceptual idea put forth in number
and it's not not that hard to understand
so, the idea of ascending out of base
consciousness is to go from the beast
to
complete consciousness or unity
consciousness, to go from 666 to 777
or to go from the 9 to the 3
and this is where we get the number 93
representing
the journey out of base consciousness
from the 9 to the 3
now
we're going to look at even deeper
thelemic
numerological understanding of the
number 93 in the next slide
and this is that
both words
that are two of the most
important and
foundational
concepts and principles in
the philosophy of thelema
actually total
the exact same number
when we break them down into
greek gematria
and that means, that in the
occult tradition of thelema, in
gematria terms
they actually are the same thing, and
they mean the same thing, they are one
and the same
thelema is agape
to do the will
is
love
is true love
the true will is true love
to do the will
is to enact higher love
in creation
and, of course
anybody that understands natural law
knows this
because to enact natural law and to
teach natural law that is to be the
servant of
the force of
justice that ultimately rules creation
you're at the right hand side of that
that's the hangman card on the tarot
that sits at the right hand side of the
justice card, which represents natural
law or the godhead
and
it is one and the same with performing
an act of true love
that's to to do that great work is to
live in heart based higher love
consciousness
so, thelema means the true will, not to be
confused with will with a lower case "w"
and it totals 93 in greek gematria
in greek gematria theta is 9
epsilon is 5, lambda is 30
eta is 8, mu is 40, and alpha is
you add up those numbers and you get
9 plus 5 is 14
plus 30 is 44
plus 8 is 52
plus 40 is 92
plus 1 is 93
thelema
in
gematria terms equals 93
and, again, we have that concept of going
from the 9 to the 3
the 9 is actually a zero, it's the
trinity, again - thought, emotion, action
unified
on one accord
united, aligned
aligned with the will of creation
on the other side we have the word "agape"
in greek
representing true love, not to be
confused with love with a lowercase "l" -
the eros or philos forms of love
it also totals 93 in greek gematria
alpha is 1
gamma is 3, alpha is 1
pay is 80
you would actually pronounce pi, people
say pay in the greek
in the actual ancient greek the letter
is simply pronounced pi, like the english
letter p
it's not pay, there's no long i
sound in greek unless you combine
alpha and epsilon, then you have the
sound i
from ae
i
you know, so
truly in ancient greek the letter
that we call pay in english is pi
is pronounced pi - p-i
or it would be pay-iota if it was spelled out in greek
so
the eta at the end is 8, so, let's add
them together - 1 plus 3 is 4
plus 1 is 5, plus 80 is 85, plus 8 is
so, when we have two equivalent
numerological values in
the thelemic gematria system
it is ascribed that they mean the same
thing, and they do
see, that's the beauty of it, right, it's
not something that's nebulous here
you're not trying to say
you know
truck equals
angel or something like that, you know
not things that like don't quite
make sense
here
the attribution works
and it's perfect
because the true will is true love
to align one's will to the will of
creation is to be in a harmonious act of
love
it's...
it works out perfectly
and that's why the number 93 is so
important in the thelemic tradition
there are other numbers that have a lot
of numerological
significance, which we could briefly
touch on
so, we saw the number 93 - thelema, will
totals 93 in greek gematria
agape, love - totals 93 in greek gematria
therefore they essentially mean the same
thing
true will and true love are equivalents
of each other
the number 93 represents ascension out
of ego and duality consciousness, and
into love will and unity consciousness
as we saw to go from the beast to the
perfected being - the 777
that's not considered being god
god's number in greek gematri would be
so, man still is not the perfection that
the godhead is the 3 infinities
perfection and thought, emotion, action
but it's
completeness in the physical form in
thought, emotion and action that you're
going to reach in the physical domain
but still not god
so, you have 666, 777 and 888
so, again, to go from the 666
base or beast consciousness to the 777
man in
god-like consciousness
in
unity consciousness, non-contradictory
unified consciousness
is to go from the 9 to the 3
and, again
93 reduces to 3, so, it is
the equivalent of 777, to
say "93" is to say
man in
non-dual
unity consciousness
no contradiction in thought, emotion and
action, completeness in thought, emotion
and action
another number that's important in the
numerology
is 77 - that's missing
one of the 7s
and that's why
you
always have to incorporate the
heart-based intelligence and love
that's the foundation of everything
that's the law
love is the law
we're going to talk about that phrase
see
if you're not coming from that heart
based intelligence, and it's all
intellect and ego
you're operating at the 7-7, the 77
which is falling short of the three 7s
so, if you have two 7s out of three
7s
you could look at that as two thirds
right
and it is true, because the reduction
7 plus 7 is 14
right
then 777 is 21
that's two thirds when you reduce it, if
you divide by 7 you get 2 over
3, and then convert that to
decimal and you get a repeating 6
14 out of 21 - two thirds
which decimally is
in decimal terms is
point 666666...
total incompletion
forever
eternal incomplete if the heart is left
at
the door
that is sorcery
that is intellect combined with egoic
will, right, that's truly
"do whatever you want"
so, if you see the 77
and it's not being actively unified with
the other 7, right
there is a concept in thelema, you could
see 77 by itself, but there's always
another 7 to unify it with to bring
it into balance
but
two 7s, 7-7 or 77, left by
itself unchecked is sorcery, that's to do
the egocentric will
that's the dark occult
intellect combined with egoic will but
devoid of true care devoid of the heart
based intelligence
and then of course
77 is just one short of
the number 78, which is the total amount
of cards in the tarot deck
so
you're taking one card short of
the book of life
and ultimately
we know what card would be the short
end of the stick
if you remove
truly the heart-based intelligence and
true care from
the 78 of the tarot deck
ultimately you're taking the fool card
out
which represents the soul, because
to take the heart out of the equation of
the trinity is to lose the soul
so, ultimately, all of this has to come
out of true care, and that doesn't mean
mushy wishy-washy love, it's not eros
it's not philos, it's not
romantic love, it's not even care for
people, it's care for truth, it's care for
what is right, it is care for freedom, it
is care for justice
that's the type of heart based
intelligence we're talking about, that
has to be the foundation of everything
that doesn't mean
let's all unconditionally love everybody
even if they're murdering our children
that's not what it means
it means - i care about what is true, i
care about what is right, i care about
freedom for all
agape-love
once you remove that you've destroyed
the soul
and that's where most people are at in
the world today, they don't care about
what's right, they don't care about truth
they don't care about love
from a higher perspective, they don't
care about freedom, they have no true
care
for anything
they don't even want to know what's
going on, they want to live selfish
purposeless lives
and that's basically the destruction of
the soul and being turned into a golem, a
flesh robot
so, very powerful that removing the
one 7 gives us the number that is
one short of the total number of cards
in the tarot
and obviously you're removing the first
card of the major arcana, the fool, which
is the soul card
the number 23, another important number
in thelemic gematria representing getting
out
escape
but not in escapist terms, it meaning
escaping mind control, the term "23
skidoo" was a big thing in the 1920s or
30s
trying to think when it even originated
i think it was the 1920s
it meant like getting out of the
situation that you're in, like if you're
in a
social function, and you really don't
want to be there and it's uncomfortable
and you need to get out of there and go
do your own thing, you know
people will call it ghosting now
you did the "23 skidoo", you got out while
getting was good and easy and
zip, you're out
you know
this is in thelemic terms
a reference to that time period
obviously, you know, i believe crowley
lived into the...
i think he lived into the 40s, i have to
get his exact
birth and death date, but
certainly, this was a
popular phrase, a pop cultural phrase
during the time that he lived, and he
incorporated it into some of his
writings
in one of them he actually
calls the paragraph, or the little
section that he's
talking about, skidoo
and it's the number 23, it's the 23rd
paragraph of the writing
little play on this turn of a phrase
back in the 1920s - "23 skidoo"
getting out while the getting is good
get out of the mind controlled thought
prison into which you have been lulled
get out of the head cage
and that's the whole idea is
it was
don't wait
get out while you can, while the
information is available, while you have
the opportunity, because these sorcerers
of consciousness are going to be
refining their techniques and making it
harder and harder for people to get out
of the head cage
of mind-controlled consciousness
so
that is what he's saying the "23"
represented
take advantage of the opportunity to get
out while the getting is good
then we have the
number
418 which is
obviously adds to 13 - 4 plus 1 is 5, plus
8 is 13, again, a number associated with
traditionally bad luck
but in this
case
thelema ascribes it to
a magical term of manifestation, what in
other forms of magic was abracadabra, in
thelema it is abrahadabra
they call it "the word of the aeon"
it is the word that means the great work
has been accomplished
or at least
what you are trying to bring into
alignment with
the will of creation
that an aspect of that has been done and
the word
abrahadabra translates
as
"i create as i speak" or "as i speak i
create" - it's what i talk about all the
time in my work that
the universe is spoken into existence
we create the situation that we are
experiencing by the power of our voice
and if we're not using our voice wisely
we're not creating wisely, if we're not
putting the information out there to
others with our voice, because of
whatever problem we have doing that
whatever courage or block, whatever lack
of courage, cowardice, trauma or block we
have going on in our minds, and in our
whole
personality
that is disallowing us from doing that
we're
acting as a
preventative or a stressor, in that
regard, to not allow us to do that
we are not putting our voice forward and
doing what is right, what we know we
should be doing
especially at a time of tyranny and
slavery
so
he called this "the word of the aeon of
horus"
because he felt...
in thalemic
world view, i guess, you could say
thelemites and crowley himself looked at
that we were emerging from a time period
that
was a darker time period
and a constraint on human freedom
constraint on human potential
and, certainly, that is true
he looked at that we would be emerging
if
a true occult revival were to take place
in the world
driven by
people in the modern age putting this
information out
would give birth to what he referred to
as the aeon of horus, which was the
bright conquering solar child
meaning that light would be coming to
the world, the light of knowledge, the
light of
truth, the light of the creator of the
universe, emerging
and it would be
enlightening souls
with knowledge that they would carry on
to others and
use their flame to ignite
the flame of the minds of others
so, it's a great concept the aeon of
horus
and
again
it represents the great work being
accomplished and
manifesting a better result for everyone
so, 418 is a
pretty positive
gematria
numerology attribution in thelema
the next concept in thelema i want to
cover is what crowley meant by magic
which he spelled with a k
as opposed to the traditional spelling
m-a-g-i-c, he spelled it m-a-g-i-c-k to
distinguish it from
forms of illusionism
you know
basically pop culture magic
he's not talking about the magicians
that go and make, you know, the statue of
liberty appear to disappear
which is all
little nonsense tricks and misdirection
he was talking about actually using the
power of the voice
and the power of suggestion to truly
influence the minds of other people at a
distance
so, this is what i've been doing since
day one, straight out in the open make no
bones about it, just outright telling
people
i consider myself a magician in the
sense of the thelemite tradition, because
what it really means is to influence
others with the power of your voice
influence others by educating them
often or almost always at a distance, not
even having to be in their presence
communicating the sound and power of the
voice, the vibration of the voice over
long distances with
technological means
that's magick
if i could change one person's life
that's magick, magick has been performed
think about it
you've never touched the person, you've
never actually physically been in their
presence
you got ideas to them that they paid
attention to listen that were expressed
that were then understood, they were
translated into their understanding in
their mind and then they acted upon them
and changed their lives for the better
there's no better definition of magick
in thelemic terms magick is seen as, and
it's defined as, the science and art of
influencing change to occur in
accordance with the will, notice
capital "w" underlined - the will of
creation
so, i'm not performing magick if i'm
selfishly trying to get what i want, and
influence people to help me obtain that
i'm performing magick if i'm explaining
to people what is the will of creation
how do you align your personal will to
that, how do you align your behavior to
that, do you understand objective
morality and natural law, are you
initiating harm, do you know you need to
stop doing that, are you lying to
yourself
about what's really going on in the
world, do you know you need to stop doing
that, how do you do those things
what kind of sacrifice might you
have to make to do those things - it
involves sacrifice
but
the magick itself is when you're actually
attempting to
almost always at a distance
influence
change to occur in accordance with the
higher will
crowley and many other
occultists of his time period, like
helena blavatsky, distinguished magick
from what they referred to as sorcery
what i would call the dark occult
which is the diametric opposite of magick
it is to attempt to influence change to
occur in accordance with one's own
selfish lower case "w"-will
the will of the sorcerer, the will of the
practitioner of that influence or
manipulation, see, that's where it's not
even influence
it's manipulation
you know, i could write it like this
that's a better definition
sorcery is the attempt to manipulate
change to occur in accordance with one
selfish will
i don't even have to say attempt
better
so, that was the difference in thelema
between magick and sorcery, and i talked
about that very early on in what on
earth is happening work
in the earlier podcasts
the next concept in thelema is known as
the holy guardian angel, and i'm just
going to briefly touch on it, we'll have
to continue this next week, because we're
rapidly running out of time
crowley seen the holy guardian angel as
a deep connection, a deeper connection to
the higher self, which would then help
guide us toward our true will and our
ultimate grand purpose in life
before that to manifest in our lives we
have to learn to listen to its wisdom
the path of right action that's telling
us to undertake by quieting the voice of
the ego, this is what some of the
thelemic practices were about
to help us to hear that voice meditative
and yogic practices
crowley called his own guardian angel
aiwass, whose name
also totals 93 in greek gematria
so, i think this is an excellent place to
leave it, and we can continue talking
about that at the beginning of next
week's show where we will do
the philosophy of thelema part two, and
we'll expand on this even more next week
ladies and gentlemen, thank you for
watching this episode of what on earth
is happening
remember, government
is slavery
we'll see you right here next week
everyone, thank you
[Music]